Curriculum Vitae

KC Sivaramakrishnan

Computer Laboratory University of Cambridge

February 17, 2015

15 JJ Thomson Avenue Cambridge CB3 0FD Tel: +44 79828 42499

Summary

I am interested in the design and implementation of concurrent programming languages targeting scalable platforms such as many-core processors and compute clouds. My research spans programming models, compilers, static analysis, schedulers, threading systems, and memory management.

Education

PhD — Computer Science

May 2011 - Dec 2014 Purdue University, USA

Thesis Title: Functional Programming Abstractions for Weakly Consistent Systems

Advisor: Suresh Jagannathan

Aug 2008 – May 2011

Master of Science — Computer Science

Purdue University, USA

GPA: 3.94/4 Bachelor of Engineering — Computer Science and Engineering

Aug 2004 - May 2008

GPA: 9.55/10

Anna University, India

PSG College of Technology

Experience

Research Associate, University of Cambridge

Advisor: Anil Madhavapeddy

Dec 2014 - present Cambridge, UK

I am working on a variety of projects under the OCaml Labs initiative in the Computer Laboratory.

Research Assistant, Purdue University

Advisor: Suresh Jagannathan

Aug 2008 - Dec 2014

West Lafayette, IN, USA

My research focused on discovering new language abstractions and developing runtime system techniques to ease programming weakly consistent systems. To this end, I have built MultiMLton, a parallel and distributed extension of MLton Standard ML compiler and runtime and Quelea, a shallow extension of Haskell for declarative programming over eventually consistent data stores.

Teaching Assistant, Purdue University

Undergraduate C Programming (CS180) Graduate Programming Languages (CS565)

West Lafayette, IN, USA

Aug 2012 - Dec 2012

Aug 2011 - Dec 2011

My tasks included designing and evaluating weekly projects, office hours for one-on-one instruction, and grading.

Research Intern, Microsoft Research, Cambridge

Advisors: Tim Harris, Simon Marlow, and Simon Peyton Jones

Feb 2012 - May 2012

Cambridge, UK

I developed a concurrency substrate for Glasgow Haskell Compiler (GHC) to allow programmers to modularly implement user-level schedulers and concurrency libraries for Haskell threads in Haskell, without having to re-engineer critical runtime system components. The concurrency substrate is built around one-shot continuations and uses transactional memory for coordination.

Research Intern, Samsung Information Systems America (R&D)

Advisor: Daniel Waddington

May 2010 - Aug 2010

San Jose, CA, USA

I was part of the core team that developed SNAPPLE programming language - a safe and concurrent extension of C++ targeted at many-core processors. The task involved designing language extensions for concurrency, compiler extensions for safety, and a runtime for executing large number of lightweight threads. SNAPPLE was implemented as a veneer on top of C++ using LLNL Rose source-to-source compiler.

Intern, Advanced Numerical Research and Analysis Group

Dec 2007 - Apr 2008 Advisor: Sankar Chnab Hyderabad, India

As a part of the Compiler Engineering group, I ported Kaffe, an open source Java VM to an embedded microprocessor ANUPAMA and a desktop processor ABACUS. Developed a lightweight threading subsystem, and implemented a JIT backed for ABACUS.

Journal Publications

Migrating MultiMLton to the Cloud

W4

W3

ML Workshop

KC Sivaramakrishnan, Lukasz Ziarek, Suresh Jagannathan

Daniel G. Waddington, Chen Tian, KC Sivaramakrishnan

Workshop on Systems for Future Multi-Core Architectures (SFMA)

Scalable Lightweight Task Management Schemes for MIMD Processors

J2	MultiMLton: A Multicore-aware Runtime for Standard ML KC Sivaramakrishnan, Lukasz Ziarek, Suresh Jagannathan Journal of Functional Programming (JFP), 24(6): 613 – 674	Nov 2014
J1	Efficient Sessions KC Sivaramakrishnan, Mohammad Qudeisat, Lukasz Ziarek, Karthik Nagaraj, Patrick Eugster Science of Computer Programming (SCP), 78(2): 147 – 167 Invited paper	Feb 2013
❖ Conference Publications		
C7	Declarative Programming over Eventually Consistent Data Stores KC Sivaramakrishnan, Gowtham Kaki, Suresh Jagannathan International Conference on Programming Language Design and Implementation (PLDI)	Jun 2015
C6	Rx-CML: A Prescription for Safely Relaxing Synchrony KC Sivaramakrishnan, Lukasz Ziarek, Suresh Jagannathan Symposium on Practical Aspects of Declarative Languages (PADL)	Jan 2014
C5	A Coherent and Managed Runtime for ML on the SCC KC Sivaramakrishnan, Lukasz Ziarek, Suresh Jagannathan Many-core Architecture Research Community Symposium (MARC) Best paper award	Nov 2012
C4	Eliminating Read Barriers through Procrastination and Cleanliness KC Sivaramakrishnan, Lukasz Ziarek, Suresh Jagannathan International Symposium on Memory Management (ISMM)	Jun 2012
C3	Composable Asynchronous Events Lukasz Ziarek, KC Sivaramakrishnan, Suresh Jagannathan International Conference on Programming Language Design and Implementation (PLDI)	Jun 2011
C2	Efficient Session Type Guided Distributed Interaction KC Sivaramakrishnan, Karthik Nagaraj, Lukasz Ziarek, Patrick Eugster International Conference on Coordination Models and Languages (COORDINATION)	June 2010
C1	Partial Memoization of Concurrency and Communication Lukasz Ziarek, KC Sivaramakrishnan, and Suresh Jagannathan International Conference on Functional Programming (ICFP)	Sep 2009
❖ Workshop Publications		

Sep 2013

Apr 2011

The Design Rationale for MultiMLton

W2 Suresh Jagannathan, Armand Navabi, KC Sivaramakrishnan, Lukasz Ziarek

ML Workshop

Sep 2010

Lightweight Asynchrony using Parasitic Threads

W1 KC Sivaramakrishnan, Lukasz Ziarek, Raghavendra Prasad, Suresh Jagannathan

Workshop on Declarative Aspects of Multicore Programming (DAMP)